NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office Files. 6174/011
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- WFW-Activity Drivers Unit Work, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Grievances and related correspondence re Wappingers Federation of Workers and Wappingers CSD Activity Drivers; sports activity schedules; arbitration cases for Pines Plains Federation of Educators and others
- WFW-Counseling Memo, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Disciplinary memos to custodian and replies
- WFW-Sec. 75 Discipline, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Correspondence re hearing for charge of misconduct; letter of resignation
- Pine Plains SRP-Trust Contributions, 1991-1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Arbitration briefs re Pine Plains Central School District and Pine Plains School Related Personnel; summaries of case law re Improper Practice decisions; agreements between school district and union, 1988; related correspondence; handwritten notes
- WCT/WFW-Accruals/Pay Stub, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Letter from Wappingers school district to bargaining unit presidents re change in paystub information; case law summaries
- WCT Conference Days, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Grievance papers re denial of teacher-initiated conference day; notice of hearing; handwritten notes
- WCT-Welfare Trust Fund, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Wappingers Congress of Teachers letter to attorneys re district's audit of union welfare trust fund
- WCT Teacher Initiated Conference Day, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Grievance re denial of teacher-initiated conference day
- Wappingers Congress of Teachers, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Correspondence
- WCT-MOA Release Time, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Letter of Agreement between Wappingers Central School District and Wappingers Congress of Teachers
- WCT-Signed MOA, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Memorandum of Agreement between Wappingers Central School District and Wappingers Congress of Teachers resolving mediation over administration of EpiPen injections to students in anaphylactic emergencies; correspondence re mediation issues, especially training
- WCT-Legal Review, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Correspondence and chronology re claim against the district by excessed tenured school psychologist; case law summaries
- WCT-Webster In School Suspension, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Letter to district from Wappingers Congress of Teachers requesting employment history of all in-house suspension teachers; handwritten notes
- WCT-Private Student IEP's, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Correspondence re special education teachers and annual reviews of students placed in private schools or being home schooled; handwritten notes
- WCT, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Draft of Pine Plains policy re school closures for inclement weather; letter from district re suspension with pay for fraudulent billing as trustee of union welfare fund; 3020-a checklist, request for hearing
- Learning Center Advisorship, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Proposal for pilot program; Memorandum of Agreement between Wappingers district and union
- WFW-Written Reprimand, 1979-1998 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Written reprimand and related memos recommending suspension of bus driver for use of inappropriate language; letters of complaint from parents
- Wappingers Federation of Workers -General, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Correspondence; subpoena
- WFW-Layoff Benefits, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  Grievance and decision re layoff of mechanic; handwritten notes; related correspondence
- WCT, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  Description of charges against teacher, request for 3020-a hearing, and checklist; handwritten notes
- Livingston Manor TA-Bus Driver, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  Bus drivers' daily reports; transportation requests; disciplinary letters from Livingston Manor Central School to bus driver for insubordination
- WCT Case 444, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  Grievance form requesting removal of formal observation report from employee's file
- Livingston Manor-Sick Leave, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  Letter to Livingston Manor superintendent re leave policy and charge of excessive use; related correspondence
- Livingston Manor Bargaining, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  Tentative Agreement for Negotiations for Teaching Staff
- Livingston Manor Bargaining, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  1991-92 instructional salary data; memo re settlement, August 15, 1991; 1992-93 negotiated contract between district and non-teaching association; 1991-92 contract with teachers' association; teacher association negotiation survey; comparisons of workload among locals; Sullivan County bargaining roundup (1992-93 settlements)
- Livingston Manor, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  Correspondence re termination of employee, total disability
- Livingston Manor, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  Complaints re use of corporal punishment; caution memo /superintendent's report; handwritten statement from teacher; handwritten note from school nurse; text of policy prohibiting corporal punishment
- Livingston Manor Tenure Denial, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  Letter of termination, June 8, 1995; annual evaluation, June 14, 1995; observation, December 8, 1994; rebuttal to evaluation, January 30, 1995; letter of commendation, April 4, 1995
- Wappinger's Cafeteria Workers General, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  Collective Bargaining Agreement between Wappingers Central School District and Wappingers Cafeteria Association, July 1, 1989, through June 30, 1992; related documents
- WCW-Gerry Copogna Pension, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  Correspondence re retroactive eligibility for Teachers Retirement System
- TRD 803-Retroactive Membership, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  Court decision; correspondence
- Red Hook SRP Job Descriptions n.d. (Box 6, Folder 32)
  Job descriptions for cook, cook manager, food service helper
- Red Hook SRP Factfinding, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  Memorandum on Behalf of the Association, to PERB, in the matter of factfinding between Red Hook School Related Personnel Association and Red Hook Central School District; settlement memorandum of agreement
- Red Hook SRP General, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  Letter from NYSUT labor relations specialist Steven Berman to John Brontoli re continuation of health insurance, retirement questions; memo to Berman from Margaret-Mary K. Martel, president of Red Hook School Support Staff Association, asserting sole authority to make decisions affecting membership
- Pines Plains Correspondence, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  Correspondence re grievances, Summer Leadership Conference, change in health insurance plans; letter from Pine Plains district superintendent to president of Pine Plains Federation of Educators, warning her not to speak to him again in an inappropriate tone of voice
- Red Hook SRP, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  Grievance re breach of contract over bid run; letter advising bus driver that he was reassigned to the run
- Red Hook SRP-Salary, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  Letter from district denying grievance re salary; memorandum of agreement; list of bus assignments; drivers' hours; handwritten notes
- Welfare Funds, 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  Lists of employee welfare/benefit funds in Elmsford region
- VOTE/COPE, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  Memo re payroll deduction plan for VOTE/COPE
- Roscoe TA, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  Correspondence; long document, "Spring Events Regarding Defamation and Harassment at Work"
- Worker's Compensation, 1988-1994 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  Materials re Workers' Compensation process in New York; claim form; document, "A Guide to Workers' Compensation Benefits for Occupational Illness"; correspondence
- Waterford TA, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  Memos to NYSUT general counsels and regional staff directors re PERB decision re Watertown teacher salaries and proposed rules re injunctive relief
- Weingarten Rights, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  Discussion of right to union representation at disciplinary meetings, with attached decision by Administrative Law Judge in the matter of Buffalo Teachers Federation, charging party, and City School District of the City of Buffalo, respondent
- Unemployment Insurance, 1987-1992 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  Legal briefs; memos re "reasonable assurance" of return to work
- Arbitrability, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  Opinion and award of arbitrator in the matter of the arbitration between State of New York (Department of Social Services) (employer) and Public Employees Federation (union); summaries of case law
- Roscoe 3020-A-Katz, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  Text of 3020-a charges against teacher for grading students incorrectly; related documents
- Rhinebeck Negotiations, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  Text of 3020-a charges against teacher; related correspondence
- NPUT-Al Fiore, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  New Paltz United Teachers grievance form re reassignment of tenured teacher; NYSUT Memorandum in Support of Arbitrability; Memorandum on Behalf of Employer; opinion and award; related correspondence and documentation, including lesson observations
- WCT-Osterc, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  3020-a checklist; description of charges against Wappingers Falls teacher for insubordination and incompetence
- WCT-Inappropriate Behavior, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  3020-a checklist; description of charges against Wappingers Falls teacher for misconduct/inappropriate behavior
- WCT-Inappropriate Language, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  3020-a checklist; description of charges against Wappingers Falls teacher for misconduct/inappropriate language and incompetence
- WCT-Privacy Issues, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Freedom of Information Law request; text of law re exempt records; legal memo from NYSUT counsel; employee files provided in response to FOIL request
- WCT-Tenure Denial, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Correspondence re tenure denial, letter of recommendation; teacher observation reports
- WCT-Conrad Gagnon, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Description of 3020-a charges against Wappingers Falls teacher for abuse of sick leave and insubordination; State Education Department disciplinary proceeding report and recommendations; supporting documentation and correspondence
- WCT-IP #2 Psychologists, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Consultant's agreement for short-term psychological services with Wappingers Falls school district; notice of claim (Improper Practice charge) against district by Wappingers Congress of Teachers for contracting out work of school psychologists
- WCT-IP #1 Psychologists, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Notice to PERB that Wappingers Congress of Teachers was withdrawing its Improper Practice charge against the district for contracting out psychological services; Improper Practice charge; PERB appearance and answer; related correspondence
- WCT-Length of Workday, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Grievance re length of workday, timing of formal observation; related notes and correspondence
- WCT-Termination, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Letter of termination; letter from Mark requesting reasons for termination; letter rescinding resignation; letter noting error in term of probationary appointment; teacher observations
- Red Hook AAA, 1986-1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  School district's brief in the matter of arbitration between Red Hook School Related Employees' Association and Red Hook Central School District; Association's Submission; Post Hearing Brief of Association; transcript of proceedings; arbitration summary; opinion and award; bus driver daily reports; handwritten notes
- Red Hook SRP-Unit Work, 1990-1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Demand for Arbitration against district for performing bargaining unit work by administrator (driving field hockey team to game); grievances; related correspondence; bus drivers' daily reports
- WFW-Health Insurance, 1992-1997 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Collective bargaining agreement between Wappingers Central School District and Wappingers Cafeteria Association, July 1, 1992 through June 30, 1997; summation in the matter of arbitration between Wappingers Federation of Workers and Wappingers Central School District; opinion and award; post-hearing brief of the association; handwritten notes from several meetings; grievance materials; correspondence and background information re dual insurance coverage, buyout
- PPSRP-Welfare Trust Fund, 1988-1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Agreement between Pine Plains Central School District and Pine Plains School Related Personnel; grievance claiming money owed by district to PPSRP Welfare Fund, December 14, 1993; opinion and award in the matter of arbitration between Pine Plains School Related Personnel and Pine Plains Central School District re Union Welfare Fund Payments; NYS Supreme Court Appellate Division decision and order, April 8, 1996
- TAS-Transportation Advisory Services, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Letters of recommendation from various school districts supporting efficiency study by Transportation Advisory Services; Wappingers Federation of Workers Talking Points Regarding Student Transportation Efficiency Study Interim Report, criticizing study; memo re settlement of subcontracting grievance, January 28, 1998
- Privatization, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  AFT Privatization Clips: An Update on For-Profit Schools (newspaper clippings); NYSUT booklet, "Privatization: Could It Happen in Your Local?" September 1997; cover letter re workshop, October 17, 1997; draft document, "Critical Factors to Consider in Dealing with Proposals to Privatize"
- Delta Dental, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  Description of Delta Dental plan; proposed plan comparison; cover memo
- WFW-Board of Education, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Memoranda from Wappingers district Board of Education re statement of principles and policies, comments and suggestions for action, and directions to superintendent
- WFW-WCT-WFEA Court Case Salary, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  Verified complaint in U.S. District Court against Wappingers School District et al.; response by district; statement in opposition by Wappingers Congress of Teachers, Wappingers Cafeteria Association, Wappingers Federation of Workers, Wappingers Federation of Educational Assistants (via NYSUT legal counsel), September 15, 1995; related correspondence and documents
- WFW Activity Drivers, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Correspondence re work schedule, grievance, arbitration
- WFW-Discipline, 1994-1997 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  Correspondence re termination of bus driver for failing random drug test; grievance; arbitration opinion and award
- WFW-Discipline, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  Certified letter from Wappingers district to Hogan re charge of misconduct (theft) and suspension without pay
- WFW-Grievance, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  Letter from district re grievance arbitration for old case, suggesting union withdraw
- Arbitration Prep Materials, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  Agenda for Cornell ILR Labor Workshop Series re Arbitration Advocacy, February 19, 1985; book chapters re arbitrability and related topics; contract analysis checklist; newsletter from Baruch College (CUNY) National Center for the Study of Collective Bargaining in Higher Education and the Professions
- Americans with Disabilities Act, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  Outline of presentation, "Complying with the Americans with Disabilities Act," Industrial Relations Research Association, Hudson Valley Chapter, April 15, 1992; newsletter, Preventive Strategies for Employers, February/March 1992
- Arbitration Awards, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  Opinions and awards, Wappingers Central School District and Wappingers Federation of Transit, Custodial, and Maintenance Workers, 1987; Wappingers Federation of Workers and Wappingers Congress of Teachers and Wappingers Central School District, 1984; Public Employees Federation (PEF) and State of New York Department of Labor, 1984 and 1983; United University Professions and State of New York (State University of New York); PEF and Division for Youth, 1980; Summary of Civil Service Law; Hyde Park Teachers Association and Hyde Park Central School District, 1985; Amsterdam Teachers Association and Greater Amsterdam School District, 1977; glossary of legal terms
- Tri Valley English Curriculum, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  Memos re meeting for proposed high school English curriculum; bus driver seniority list; run bids; memo re driver refresher course
- Wapp. Cafeteria Association-Mediation/Arbitration Retroactive Pay/Personal Leave, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  PERB arbitration case between Wappingers Cafeteria Association and Wappingers Central School District; handwritten notes; related correspondence
- Arbitrator Award List (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Arbitration award list by arbitrator, including issues and locals
- Membership Reporting, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  NYSUT publication, Membership Reporting and Dues Transmittal 84-85
- OSHA Rep., 1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Minutes of NYSUT Health and Safety Reorganization meeting
- PERB Mediation/Arbitration, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Preliminary Guidelines Regarding Staff Grievance Med/Arb Pilot Project for Local Governments and School Districts; form, NYS Public Employment Relations Board Joint Request for Staff Grievance Med/Arb
- Personal, 1985-1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Newsletter, Mid-Hudson School Bell, June 1985; letter to NYSUT director of Field Services Robert Allen from Vermont Federation of Teachers, thanking him for assigning two NYSUT field reps to AFT project in Vermont, June 24, 1985
- PSA, 1989-1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  Professional Staff Association salary schedule; NYSUT-PSA Proposed Agreement for 9/1/89-8/31/92; Empire Blue Cross and Blue Shield Dental Fee Schedule
- Salary Schedules Training, 1986-1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  Examples of types of salary schedules
- School Grad., 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  Papers by Steven Berman for various labor classes, "Labor Divided: The Teamsters and U.A.W. and the AFL-CIO," May 15, 1980; "Public and Private White Collar Unionism in Great Britain," spring 1981; "The Duty of Fair Representation," May 12, 1983; "Productivity in the Public Sector," January 4, 1983; "Portrait of a Process - Collective Negotiations in Public Employment," March 24, 1983; correspondence
- Shared Decision Making, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  Text of the Commissioner's Regulations; NYSUT Information Bulletins
- School District Profiles, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  List of district profiles indicating enrollment, staffing, wealth, expenditures, and teacher salaries
- Red Hook-O'Neill, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  Collective bargaining agreement between Red Hook Faculty Association and Red Hook Central School District, July 1986-June 1989; grievance; correspondence re termination of library media specialist
- Red Hook Health Insurance, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  Memorandum of Agreement between District and Red Hook Faculty Association (revised draft, 6/29/88); correspondence re health insurance plans
- Red Hook Construction, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  Constitution of Red Hook Faculty Association
- Red Hook-Teacher Certification, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  Correspondence re teacher certification
- Red Hook Correspondence, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  Correspondence re corrective actions as alternative to termination of library media specialist; local association survey
- Red Hook Exposure Control Policy, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Fact sheet re medical wastes by Division of Hazardous Substances Regulation, August 1990; document, Preventing AIDS and Hepatitis in Schools: NYS PESH Bloodborne Disease Regulations; Rhinecliff Union Free School District Exposure Control Plan: Draft of Policy on Occupational Exposure to Bloodborne Pathogens, January 27, 1993
- Red Hook-SRP Agreement, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  Draft agreement between district and Red Hook School Related Employees Association, with cover letter, March 17, 1988
- Red Hook SRP General, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  Memo re sick bank request; memo re use of staff volunteer drivers for athletic trips; seniority list for teacher aides, 1991; agreement re retroactive pay for two employees, 1990
- Red Hook F.A. Break Time, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  Opinion and award in the matter of arbitration between Red Hook Central School District and Red Hook Faculty Association re break time
- Red Hook SRP, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  Accident report; disciplinary letter; letters of support; report of meeting
- Red Hook, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  Correspondence with State Education Department, SUNY College at New Paltz, and Red Hook school district re questionable certification for driver's ed instructor; copies of transcripts; letter of resignation
- Red Hook SRP Asbestos Handling, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  Red Hook Central School Asbestos Inspections A.H.E.R.A. 10/12/88; minutes of special Board of Education meeting; request for negotiations for additional compensation for duties involving handling of asbestos; notification of promotion of staff member; withdrawal of grievance for failure to promote; demand for arbitration; withdrawal of demand
- Tri Valley Bargaining, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  Salary schedules; Tri-Valley Teachers Association Proposed Changes and Additions for 1991-92 Contract, March 1991; highlights of negotiated agreement; memo re Sullivan County settlements, February 6, 1991
- NPUT-Grievance Teaching Hours, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  Memo and grievance over teaching hours, teaching load
- NPUT B.R. Training, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  New Paltz United Teachers Officer and Building Rep Manual; handwritten notes
- NPUT Grievances, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  Grievances re letter of reprimand, salary increment
- NPUT Grievances, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  Guide for Student Teaching: A Handbook for Student Teachers and Personnel of Schools Cooperating in the Student Teacher Program (Competency-Based Teacher Education Program), State University of New York, College at New Paltz; grievances on a variety of issues; handwritten notes
- NPUT-Middle School, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  Grievances re excess supervisory duty, extension of work day
- NPUT-Failure to Post Vacancy, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  Grievance for failure to post vacancy notice
- NPUT-Sabbatical Leave, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  Grievance for denial of sabbatical leave
- NPUT-Salary Credit, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  Grievance re salary; summary of arbitration decision; correspondence; handwritten notes
- Staff Assignments, 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  Local assignments; staff bargaining load by contract expiration
- AIDS, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  Memo to NYSUT bargaining staff re AIDS Operational Policy, urging caution when negotiating with school districts, with attached NYSUT Position Paper on Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS), January 12, 1988
- Consultant Teacher Services, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  NYSUT Information Bulletin re Consultant Teacher Services
- Correspondence In, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  Letter to field representative Steve Berman, Mid-Hudson Regional Office, inviting him to AFT-paid New Staff School at George Meany Center for Labor Studies; miscellaneous letters
- Red Hook, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  Memo to Red Hook Faculty Association from district re Improper Practice charge over kindergarten and art teachers; memo re tenure area inquiry for special education teacher; document re administrative expectations for teacher teams; handwritten notes
- Wages, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  Prevailing wages for Dutchess and Sullivan counties, from NYS Department of Labor
- Red Hook SRP Contracts, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  Handwritten notes
- Red Hook SRP Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  Fact sheet re Red Hook School Related Employees Association; list of officers; letter to association from NYSUT regional office, urging members to write to state legislators opposing tuition tax credit proposal
- Red Hook Disqualifying Driver, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  Letter from Red Hook Central School District to bus driver, citing medical report as disqualifying driver from continuing in position; handwritten notes
- Red Hook SRP-Constitution, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 42)